IDOR is a great vulnerability type because it's
often high or even critical impact, yet the bug
itself is usually not so complex. However, what
often prevents us from finding IDORs is predicting
the identifier of another user. It's also not
clear to me if an IDOR will be accepted if the
authorization check is not there, but you cannot
predict the identifier of another user. So that's
why I did the case study where I extracted all
the IDOR reports from the internet and I studied
them. In this video I will show you what types
of identifiers were vulnerable to IDORs. Enjoy!
So during this case study I categorized what type
of ID was present in the report and I have eight
different categories of those identifiers. The
most common one was decimal ID, shorter than eight
digits. It was about one third of all reports and
it is a very simple case where the identifier is
easily brute forcible. You know eight digits, less
than eight digits, it's something you can brute
force in maximally a few days. But we saw big
companies making mistakes with these. Here we have
a $10,000 bug in Apple where there was an order ID
with seven digits and it was easily brute forcible
and it's just the most simple version of IDOR. You
have a request which takes the identifier, it's a
GET request, supposed to read data and it reads
data of anyone no matter what identifier you put
there. So this is the most basic IDOR that we can
see but it was very present. We'll continue with
more examples after the sponsor break. This video
is sponsored by AppSecEngineer. It's a security
training that I can honestly recommend because
myself I took a Kubernetes security course a long
time ago before this collaboration. The training
was really clear and useful with a lot of hands-on
exercises on well-prepared infrastructure. It was
a great way to kick start learning a completely
new area for me. They cover all the topics
from cloud security, DevSecOps to basic or
advanced AppSec topics. They won't bore you with
long articles or lectures. They have hundreds of
hands-on labs, courses and challenges. So whether
you're a security engineer who wants to exploit
vulnerabilities or a developer who wants to learn
secure coding or maybe a cloud engineer who needs
to secure complex cloud infrastructure, you
will definitely find something for you. To start
learning now go to AppSecEngineer.com. Another
case with the simplest ID. We have yahoo nine and
a half thousand dollars and let's skip the setup
part of the report. Here the case is a little bit
different because I also in the full version of
the case study in BBR Premium Archive you can
also see the different functionalities that were
vulnerable to those IDers and the impact of IDers.
And the interesting thing I saw that reading data
was not the most common functionality for IDers.
So the case like we saw before on Apple where
you just send a get request and you get the data
it's not the most common one because often
it was a request supposed to modify something
or to change something like here we have post
to follow some user on some yahoo application
and in the response even though this request isn't
made to strictly to read some data in the response
it returns us data of of the victim in this case
it's even an error message so it explains it a
little bit but it was it was quite common that
it wasn't the simple read operation that was
vulnerable and in terms of ID we also have the the
very simple ID I'm not sure if it's this one or
this one being brute force but doesn't matter both
are really really easily brute forcible and nine
and a half thousand dollars for this report. Then
the next group was also decimal but with eight or
more digits and we also had really really big
companies making mistakes for example we have
49 and a half thousand dollars back in Facebook
or to be precise in Instagram and you could you
just had the upload ID which as you can see
is longer than eight digits it wouldn't be
so easily brute forcible if you had to go through
the whole range because this is 13 digits but
in a lot of cases when the ID is numeric you can
just you don't have to go through the whole range
you just increment this or decrement this and you
can access data or in this case you can change
thumbnails of reels of other users and this
attack was was rewarded with 45 000 dollars
of bounty and four and a half thousand dollars
of bonus so really nice report and another case
in Facebook this time in in workplace and here
we have a little bit different case because here
again the ID looks to be numeric we don't really
know how long this is if if this is the actual
length of this identifier but here the attacker
didn't mention brute forcing the the community ID
but he retrieved the community
ID from another endpoint actually
the hunter mentioned that when submitting
the report he didn't know the way to leak
the the company ID so the attack scenario that
he used was brute force or using an ex-employee
of the company and this attack scenario is quite
interesting if you have any security mechanism
that relies on randomness of the identifier
one of the problems you will inevitably hit
is how to take access from someone like if
you have any object inside the organization
you also usually have the functionality to
kick someone out of the organization but if
your security model relies on randomness of
the identifier then you cannot take this from
that person in in this case you would have to
rotate all the IDs when kicking anyone from the
organization so when you have a report where the
company relies on randomness of the ID you should
always think or write about the attack scenario of
removing user removing access of a particular user
next we have paypal and another case where the
identifier is longer is too long to like brute
force it as a number but the identifiers were
incremental so you couldn't go through the whole
range but you could just brute force the the
particular here i think the attacker enumerated
the hunter enumerated IDs from one of his accounts
to another of his accounts so he would catch all
the accounts in between and here it it was quite
a severe bug because you could make transfers from
account of another person on paypal one thing
i want to mention here is be careful when you
are brute forcing identifiers i had this case
recently where i started a brute force attack
on on the identifiers because i thought my either
might work if i hit an account in a correct state
and i wanted to brute force like 20 000 ids and
i went went out to the gym and when i was out of
my of my home away from my computer i thought that
if this attack starts working for example after 10
000 ids and i get 10 000 requests with user data
with real user data on the production environment
i might get into trouble because companies don't
like this and they may not pay you a bounty if
you access too much customer information so it's
always safer to just access data from your other
account than brute forcing through ids even if
they are easily brute forcible with this set we
will go to the next group which is the name or
or the email in in this case sometimes it would
be the the email is often vulnerable with iders
in the change password functionality this is of
course very severe because if you can change
the password of the victim just like this it's
an account takeover back so it's probably even
worse than the either in this case it's always
1200 dollars but there were more severe ones as
well and sometimes the idlers were just on the
name here we have the report which i covered
on my channel by franz rosen where you don't
actually read the data you don't actually write
the data but you delete in this case he deleted
apple shortcuts and he actually broke the whole
mechanism for everyone on using apple shortcuts
in this case he deleted something called
zone and it was default zone doesn't really
matter what what it means it makes sense in
context of this report and i think he got 28
000 for for this bug as i said i covered it on my
channel so i will link it down in the description
in another case where you had an
idler using the name is here on reddit
where you can access mod logs and also you just
use subreddit name so this is easier than than
any identifiers because you don't even have to
brute force anything you just take the name that
you want and and you get get whatever data is
being leaked to you in in case of the either
so this is very simple case this
is easy easy life for for hunters
what isn't easy life is uuids these are long
identifiers which sometimes companies rely on
their security when they use those type of
identifiers but it's not always a good idea
i've never hacked an uber but i think
they relied or rely heavily on the
randomness of the identifiers which
sometimes doesn't work well in this case
we have the attack where you can send the
identifier and back you get the email i think
some time ago i also saw the sort of opposite of
this attack where you could send the the email and
get back the identifier and with the identifier
you could you could get an actual sensitive data
so these are some of the ways that you can do when
you have an either but you don't have a way to
to predict the identifier it's good to you
know submit some in this case i think it's
support ticket to cause some error to to maybe
get this information from the error response
but sometimes you don't have to predict
the identifier here we have google and
we can see the identifier is long doesn't look
brute forcible and actually sometimes there are
a few versions of those uuids and version one
for example even though it looks as equally as
random as this one it's not really that
random when you take a look at how it's
how it's being created so long doesn't mean
doesn't mean secure but in this case the hunter
did not find a way to predict the identifier but
he didn't have to because the functionality here
was deleting some shareable files so by definition
when someone shares something with you and you
can delete it you don't need to predict this
identifier because you are deleting something
that that they've already shared with you so you
can get away with not predicting the identifier
in a case like this but of course when you
can do it it will always always boost your
boost your payout and the next group that i
have here is called other non-brute forcible
and there were 14 cases where the report wouldn't
fall into any of those other categories but the
identifier would not be brute forcible and
one of the examples we have here it's also a
bug that i did cover on my channel it's a bug
by David Schutz about leaking private youtube
videos interestingly initially he only found
an endpoint to leak one frame of the video
and then he created a script that would sort of
recreate the idea the video from those frames so
very interesting attack but the thing is it uses
youtube ids and youtube ids are not considered
brute forcible on the here the youtube id it is
too long and too complex to be considered brute
forcible so in this case David just submitted
the report without a way to brute force the id
or without the way to predict the id and he even
mentioned here that leaking the knowing the video
id of someone's private video it would be a bug on
its own and so so the takeaway from this report is
to some companies you can report either and you
can admit that you don't have a way to predict
the identifier and they will pay you out anyway
but the problem is before submitting a report
you will have a hard time just knowing
which companies will accept this which
will not and unfortunately your best bet
is probably just submitting the report
and dealing with the possibility that they might
deny the report but 100% to companies like google
probably facebook as well i think those big big
and established bug bounty programs will accept
bugs like this another example of a value that
wasn't brute forcible but hunters were able to
to create an either is is here is a private
application which used encrypted values
for a lot of things and i also noticed that
sometimes developers use encryption hoping that
it will solve a lot of problems magically and it
shows that they don't really understand security
and they hope that just using encryption
will somehow protect them but it's often
not the case like here the hunters found the way
to generate the encrypted value or to basically
they found an endpoint that they could send
arbitrary input we have the change username path
and the response would contain the new username
encrypted so this basically gives them an endpoint
where they can encrypt whatever they want and they
knew that their invoice id i think had a specific
identifier so they changed the username to another
invoice id so they got back the encrypted an id of
someone else's invoice and then they used this
value to to get this invoice and that's how the
either worked which showed that encryption in
this case did not make things secure it only
sort of hides something from the attacker
but it doesn't really secure a lot of them
and now there are three categories left the next
one is hexadecimal eight or more digits so also
not brute forcible identifiers and we have an
example here where it's x formerly twitter program
but the thing is that the thing i want to
mention here is this this comment the hunter
referenced four different reports with ways
to disclose organization ids unfortunately
all those four reports are not none of these
are is disclosed so i cannot see the contents
but it's a very nice nice place to be where you
can reference four different reports with ways
to predict the identifier and one thing i'd like
to mention here is when i do these case studies
i start with the highest bounties and i go down to
the lowest and of course this is not a rule that's
always true but in general the quality of reports
goes down as i as i do the the case study longer
and one thing that i noticed during this case
study when when i was you know writing the
the identifier types and ways to predict
the identifiers for every single report
i noticed that in the beginning every single
report mentioned the way to disclose the
identifier or if the hunter was not able to
predict the identifier they also mentioned it
but as i went on with the case study to the lower
quality reports there were more and more ones
that that just didn't mention the the id type
sometimes the triager would ask the hunter if
they can predict the id sometimes they would not
but it just shows that the top hunters they just
think about every single aspect of exploitability
of a particular bug so it's never just okay this
is an either it's a high risk always we have to
think about how who can exploit it how do you
know the identifier do you need user interaction
all those things matter and you should be taking
all of them into consideration when writing
a report or where when preparing your exploit
with this said we'll go to the next category where
we have other so something that doesn't fit into
any other category but was brute forcible and one
of those things is a mongodb default identifiers
they also look kind of random but here we only see
that the summary is not a fully disclosed report
we see how the identifier is created and we can
see that this is relatively brute forcible number
so when you see mongodb identifiers know that they
shouldn't prevent the anyone from from
knowing the identifier of another user
and the the other report about this was here
we have the hex hexadecimal looking value
unfortunately we don't see the details it's
mentioned that the hunter mentioned that
they broke the cryptographic relationship
because between the message id and chat id
uh it it was supposedly just a simple fixed byte
increment i think i know what it means but i'm not
100 sure but yeah this was this was the only other
one in this category and finally the last category
here is a hash value which which is here and again
the hunter there are a few a few reports here
and this is also the case where initially the
three user said or the program said that they are
aware of this and they closed this report because
the hunter did not mention any way to predict the
identifier so um but as you see this this report
is in the case study so finally they they had had
to do something about it um and here the hunter
found the way to found an endpoint where they
could generate the hash it was it was using i
think the the username or it was using yeah i
found that the username of the hacker is used to
retrieve the hash but again if the hunter would
mention it in the beginning they they wouldn't
waste time on the going back and forth with the
treasure maybe they would get a higher payout
there's also a possibility that someone will
submit the same report in the time where before
you can submit your second response so there
is just a wide range of reasons to just think
about everything when submitting the report so
in total these were the types of identifiers that
i encountered during the case study if you want
to access the full article it's in bbr premium
archive also remember to check out the sponsor of
today's video appsec engineer and finally if you
want to check another video about the case study
i suggest you this one about account takeover
bugs for now thank you for watching and goodbye